and for the tutorial we will cover some
basic usage of espnet including how to
run
existing recipe and how to make a new
recipe
maybe I use our speech recognition as an
example but espnet supports many
different tasks and you can check them
in the visual document or in the GitHub
repo so here I listed several major
references here this is our GitHub repo
you can see some introduction
of the features here
and another one the second one is the
official documentation so if you want to
install espnet in a different
environment or if you want to change
some configuration for the training or
you want to try some other
notebooks you can find them here
I will check some of them later
so for this tutorial the overall
objective is to get you familiar with
espnet especially how to use an existing
recipe
and and more importantly you should know
how to find the resources if you do
encounter a specific issue with espnet
okay so let's start by the installation
espnet actually supports many different
ways to install uh this package
and here we will follow the Anaconda
based one
so before that we first Define a
function
here so this function will print the
current date and time this is used to
verify that your output is done within
this class so if you run this after the
class figure not accept it as the
checkpoint
if you get a GPU backend you can check
is GPU type here
so by running this command we can see
this is a Tesla T4 GPU it has 16 around
16 GB memory
thank you
so against the USP now we we need to
First download it so we just use give
clone to directly clone it from The
Source rifle
this should just take a few seconds
and we also check out to a specific
commit to make sure these results are
reproducible and also if you use some
earlier commits you may encounter some
problems with the installation
especially for the incompatible package
version of this number so to avoid to
avoid that we can use a disconnect
after downloading it we need to set up a
size environment to install all the
toolkeys and the USB net package so you
have multiple ways to set up a testing
environment you can do it using your
system python you can create a virtual
environment or you can download the
Anaconda and use Anaconda to manage your
packages and here we recommend this
Anaconda based approach because either
can organize the environments very well
either we are not interfere with your
other environments
and if you go to this Explorer you can
see the espnet level here
so we are now working inside the tools
folder
we are downloading the Anaconda install
it
and here we specify the environment to a
name to be espnet and the person version
to be 3.9
but espnet also supports other
different environments it has some CI
errors now but although it should work
and after setting up the environment we
need to install
some necessary required toolkits and
also install the ESPN package itself
so this step will take a long time
that you can start it
and here I just specify a particular
version for Cuda and for the title this
is a relatively new version but if you
prefer you can use some older ones or
any other thing you like
okay is there any questions about this
installation
I think it's pretty straightforward it
has a click something and you it will
start to install it
Okay so
uh when it is installed the package we
can check
some other things
like we can introduce briefly introduce
this level
so if you go to the espnet level you
will find many different directories
so
the recipes are stored in these two
folders so this is for the original USP
network speed this is what we will use
in this tutorial it contains the recipes
in ESPN2
so if we go to this uh
directory we will see many many folders
here and each folder means a different
data set we use a data set name to
specify a recipe
and the sum of the data sets has
multiple tasks for example this al4 it
has supported ASR and TDS that some
others only support one like this one
supports TDS this supports ASR
so today we will go to this am4
directory we will use asr1
and all these folders share the same
structure
so you will see many symbolic links
these are shared scripts you don't need
to change it yourself
and we also post some initial results
that was trained and that was trained by
others using ESPN ad previously
so for this data sets we have one
experiment result from Transformer
and we can check these are different
decoding configs energy results here
if you go to some other directories you
will see more comprehensive experiments
for example let's check the library
speech one
so this Library speech contains around
1000 hours of data so it's a relatively
large data set and we usually use it to
compare different methods
and in this line we have many
pre-trained models like this is
conformer Island transducer
we have some self-surprise learning
features based models
we also have some other models trained
from scratch
this is a type of encoder
and this is another type of encoder
Yeah so basically the we just use this
structure to organize these experimental
results
okay so this folder contains all the
recipes
so if you want to check the code then
most of them are located here I've got
some of them are based on the previous
version so they may be using another
folder
um
uh that is also a recipe folder for the
initial USB net we have ESPN at one
espn2s
uh you can still use it
yeah but in this tutorial we will use
the second version
the more latest
yeah that's a good question so if you go
to our official documentation
you will find something
like uh this is a brief introduction
about ESPN2 so Italy is still some
differences from the previous version
yeah it is kind of a free it is cardio
free it provides only Supply feature
extraction
and it either supports more features
yeah
so if you answer which one to start at
least we may recommend the second USB
Network yeah but if you have prior
experience you can try the first one
yeah
okay let's check
so
I think it will still take a few minutes
then we can go to this official
documentation
yeah so as I mentioned in this tutorial
I will just show you an example of a ESR
recipe but if your project involves some
other some other tasks like TTS speech
enhancement or speechless speech
translation
Etc you can find more demos here
yeah these are collected from previous
years
and about the general documentation I
think this one is important if you want
to install ESPN in a different
environment so basically to install
espnet you have to first download it
and then set up uh card is optional so
you you need to set up a price
environment and we can use Anaconda
based one which is used here and we can
use other methods to set up it
and finally you just install it
and uh so this installation step only
installs the necessary toolkits but uh
different recipes may require different
dependencies so if some recipes need
another different toolkit you can
install the customized toolkit by a few
single by a few lines of command I will
show you two examples in this part
we will need to wait for it to finish
first
okay this is about the installation
so another important thing is how to
change the configuration
so if you want to look into that you can
go to this documentation I will also
introduce some basic usages in this
tutorial but for more advanced ones you
can check this documentation
yeah it actually includes many different
features
[Music]
what they should look at
so do you use an existing task or doing
a different task I mean
yeah yeah yeah
so in this tutorial I will show you how
to use ASR tasks later yeah after we
install this but if you want to use a
different task in the next tutorial
another pH example will introduce that
how to design a new task
so Francis uh place we can see many
packages are already installed
and you just feel it takes a few minutes
okay is there any other questions
foreign
ERS here
yeah if you are familiar with this and
you train a good model then you can
contribute
foreign
oh
okay so on my side I have finished the
installation
energy
so at the end of the installation it
will show some install packages and some
other optional packages
so here we do not install all the
packages we just installed the required
ones
and if you want to install other
toolkits you can just run these commands
I will show these two examples so s3pil
can be used to use self-supervised
learning based front-ends
and the fell asleep I think the main
nailed and uh already familiar with it
so these two two okays are not used in
this tutorial
but it may be helpful in your project
okay do you have any uh issues with the
installation
if there's no issue then this is the
first checkpoint
so if you run this command this cell
you will get some outputs here
and please keep this part
do not remove this
after you've finished all the four
checkpoints you just print it as a PDF
file and submit that to the grayscope uh
so are you able to see the assignment on
grayscope
okay okay
so we have finished the installation
uh next I will show you how to use an
existing recipe
So currently espnet has supported many
many recipes and which I just showed
so if you want to see the full list you
can go to that place
and here we due to the time limit we
will use a very small
Corpus called am4 This is created in a
distributed by CMU
so
we have finished in this part let's go
to the recipe folder
so in this next in the next section we
will work inside this folder
uh in this folder we can see
some subfolders and some Scripts
and these are mostly shot across
different data sets
the configure folder is used to store
the specific configuration files
you can store your training configure
your inference configure and other
configs here
these scripts py scripts steps and utils
are shared across different recipes so
basically
you may not need to change it
and this one is used to specify the
pairs of the downloaded data set
and we will see how to use it later
this one you usually don't need to
change it
inside this one you can change the
changes how you run it because ESPN also
supports some job schedulers but here we
just run it inside this
uh terminal we don't use any job
schedule
and this is the overall entry point
so if you want to run an existing recipe
you can just check this one
you can always open this one first
and check how to use it
this is also shot across different
recipes you don't need to change it
so maybe we can
share this example this is around the
Shelf file for am4
and here you can see that it's pretty
simple
it's just the cause this Shield script
and specifies some uh
arguments here like this is a language
this is the ASR configuration file it is
used for training and this is used for
inference this is a language model
config this is for Speed perturbation
which is a type of data organization
and we also need to specify the training
set the deficit the tester says
this is used to build a dictionary build
the modeling units
like BBE character or verse this is used
to train a language model
and in this example we actually do not
use a language model because it takes
some time to train it
and we also do not use this round shell
because as you can see it just records
this air establisher and it runs
multiple stages
yeah we will run it stage by stage to
better understand this entire procedure
okay so let's start with the first stage
so basically if you want to run an
experiment you will need to do next
three things first is data preparation
you need to prepare the data and
organize this in a proper form
and so that you can efficiently load it
during training and then you you will
start training and after training you
need to decode your model on the test
set and get the influence results
finally you can run the scoring script
to get your final results like for ASR
we will use will there rate character
rate as the major Matrix
so here we will first run the data
preparation stage
it contains multiple stages
we will explain what this means
so first stage is about is called Data
preparation
it downloads the raw data Express the
entire set into a training set
validation set and test reset and we
also prepare them in the cardi format
this is probably the most uh difficult
part if you are unfamiliar with speech
and this one is Task specific so if you
prepare a new recipe you'll need to do
this yourself
for this one we just use this existing
script
and uh
let's check this script
so in the ASR the shell
you will see
many different stages and we have a
number we have an index for each stage
this is the first stage
this is the second stage the third stage
and so on
so to specify the stage uh you will need
to pass two arguments
this stage means the starting stage so
we start from the first stage and this
means the stop Stitch we stop after we
finish the first stage
and we specify the training center name
the validation set name and the test
reset name
these names are actually created by
the data preparation script
so if you check the data preparation it
calls another script here
and these names are decided by this
okay
so if you have finish into this first
stage you will see a new folder called
the data
inside that there are some subfolders
which are the splits so this is the
training result development this is a
data set and this is a test set
if you go to any of the folders you will
see some similar structures
we have four files here
and these files are the cardi format
so we have a text
which I can show here
so each line is then a corresponds to an
example and this is the reference ID for
that example this is a transcript
and these are the prepares the audio
because we need to extract the audio
from this specific format
but each line also corresponds to any
example and the first field means the
other anxiety the section of field is
how to get the audio
and this means a speaker to address so
speaker ID to all the other Trends IDs
and this one is art prints ID to speaker
ID
so other anxiety to the speaker ID if
you don't really care about the speaker
then you can use the same address ID for
the speaker ID of each others
okay so we have prepared the data so
from this one we know the ground tools
of each example the transcripts of each
sample and from this one we know well to
fetch the data
then we have both the audio and the
transcripts uh so the data preparation
is almost finished
but after that we need to do some
additional processing
so the second stage is about the speed
of perturbation this is one of the data
augmentation methods supported in
usbnets
and here we do not use it so it will
just
skip it
but in your own project you may want to
do some augmentation
and here we will for Speed operation
which doesn't change the speed of the
audio and we will store separate files
for this augmented data uh this is
different from the on the flight
developmentation like the spec augment
which you which is also supported in
dspnet
so after finishing this part we need
another stage
so we are around
this prepared data
into a specific format to more
efficiently load them during training
and I copied the
some comments some annotations from the
script
so you can understand what is this this
script does
generally we are still doing data
preparation we do not do any training
here
and after this stage we will see another
new folder called dunk these are all the
dump features including the transcripts
and the
newly organized audio files
yeah basically they still follow the
cardi Style
and so one issue is speech modeling is
that the important can have very
different lenses
so in computer vision or in natural
language processing we can usually use a
fixed size input but for speech it is
very difficult to do that
so
uh even a few very long enough for
instance can make your training very
inefficient so here we remove
some very long or very short data from
the training and the demo set but please
know that we do not remove that from the
test set
so actually you will see that the same
data set was prepared twice so one for
the real validation given 20 the other
for the inference after training
okay this part is straightforward and
the next part is to generate
the token list
here it is pretty simple we just use the
characters as the modeling unit
so if you have finished this
[Music]
um
we have arrived at the second checkpoint
let's print out the generative tokens
so basically you can see each each line
contains one separate token
there are some there are three special
tokens and the others are the characters
we have three special tokens here this
one is used for CDC modeling this is for
out of vocabulary words this is for the
inboard decoder modeling we we need to
use a special token to Mark the
beginning and the end of a sentence
so is there any questions about the data
preparation
um
so we do not change the text oh
we don't need to process the testes we
do not move the long short sequences
from the test set yeah
which also remove them from the training
and the devil
so you from this output you can see what
it has done
foreign
we copied the data from this this means
the training set
we copied it and we removed something
from our next
okay
okay so I mean in this part we did the
two things one is for the train now that
I've said the other is for the train
data set
okay I think of this part
uh let's finish it
so after data collaboration we have an
optional stage which is the language
model training
so if you want to use a language model
for decoding you will need to change it
in this stage
but here we skip it to save some time
leave your directory go to the main
training part
so here we will train an Android ASI
model
if you are unfamiliar with these
architectures they will be introduced in
some later lectures but here we just use
it as an example
so ESPN has supports many different
architectures many different laws
functions
we cannot introduce them
clearly in detail here
but we will just use it
so here we will train a small
transformer model for this small data
set
so
please create
a training config file
under the am4 ASR and configure folder
let's create a file
I will give it a name
so this is only for this demo
because the train is our family and the
Transformers
and then I have provided
training config here you can just copy
it
okay so I have the coffee and paste
please save it
once it is saved
we can use it for the later training
stages
and I will briefly introduce these
different arguments
during the training
so now let's just skip it
so for the ASR training we have two
separate stages first the stage is
called ASR connectors that as statistics
so here we collected some useful
statistics from the prepared data
uh basically we do two things one is to
collect the mean and the variance of
these features this will be used to
normalize the data
and the other thing is that we need to
collect the input data and output
sequence lens
in order to efficiently form many
batches
let's just run it
and the side note is that espnet
supports many different
on a mini batch types
so which are least which are listed in
the documentation
you can change it if you want
but in this example we will just use a
very simple one
so there is an error okay just rewind it
and sometimes we saw this error I mean
rerunning user can solve it
okay
okay so after this stage you will see
another new folder
which is experiment
and ASR status
so this contains all the collected
information
and after that we can State our start
our training
we can load the tensorboard to monitor
the training status
and please first around this cell and
then start training if you first start
training and run this
it will have to wait until this finishes
okay so we can see a blank tensorboard
here
and then we will start the training
once the training starts we will notice
another new experiment folder here
so all your training results are saved
here
and you can specify a different name for
this folder but here we just use the
default one
okay so when it is training
we can check the tensorboard
if we go to the time series
this is the training
event this is a validation event
and we have different
statistics
if you want to automatically reload data
you can turn this on
and the minimum interval is 30.
you can adjust the smoothing for the
different curves and ignore the outliers
so that you can see all the data
so during training we usually monitor
some Matrix
one metric is this accuracy
this is the average accuracy for
different tokens because we are doing
certain sequence to sequence modeling
and we can check uh like the overall
laws
you can also see
it's a learning rate curly
so here we use a learning rate scheduler
so you will see the learning rate is
changing
actually it will linearly increase and
then exponentially decay
this training will take around 12
minutes
so during training I will
explain
this configuration
so this is our training configuration
it has several different you can call it
the sections but it's not required
you just organize it this way to make it
clearer
so the first part is specify some
General configurations for the training
this is the bachelor investors
as I mentioned ESPN supports many
different batch types and we specify one
of them
if you want to learn more about that you
can just check this documentation
so I think it's very straightforward
and we specify the batch size
this is for gradient accumulation okay
can you refresh it
please refresh
okay
um okay
so do you mean this one
with the volume right
uh
so it depends on your how your token
least
so if you use characters as a model unit
then each employee is a character and
the output is also a character
prediction
and this accuracy is averaged across
different time steps
also different samples
yes yes
yeah so during training we usually do
not do this final scoring so we do not
do a full inferences and check the final
score results that do it
uh step by step
yeah so the reason is that during
inference we usually do some beam search
yeah so that is a more complicated more
expensive
so we usually don't do that on training
and also during training we can use
future forcing so we feel the ground
tools token and the check is the next
prediction but during inference you do
not have the branches
okay so if you check uh the accuracy
curve it gradually increases
and the laws gradually decreases so
overall the training is good
okay let's get back to the training
configuration
so here we specify the maximum epoch
we trained for 100 books
but this may not be sufficient for the
am4 data set
this part is specified the
initialization method you can change it
to other methods if you want
she's about to specifies
how we save the best known models so we
save it according to the maximum
accuracy
and we will also take the average of the
10 decimal models after uh all the
training finishes
and here to save time I enabled
automatically mixed precision
and I also disabled the attention plot
so if you want to check the generated
attention ways you need to increase this
one so zero means not saving any
attention plot
and this is used for data loader you can
change the number of workers
encoder means the adjusted the encoder
the user Transformer and these
configurations are specific to this
Transformer
the main Dimension is 256 it has four
attention it has
it's a linear intermediate dimension in
the field of urban network is 1024.
we repeat the same architecture 12 times
so it's a sequential model it has 12
blocks
and we use some dropouts to every part
this is the same for the decoder
and here we use the joint CDC attention
training and this this is a multitask
learning so we have attention-based
decoder we also have a CDC
added on top of the encoder so this
technique I think it will be introduced
in the lectures
and this is a label smoothing weight
we can use it to mitigate overfeeding
and this part specifies Optimizer we use
add-on and this is the peak learning
rate remember that we have a linear
scheduler so this is the maximum
learning rate
and this is the one-off steps
so if you are familiar with Transformer
if you have ever heard about Transformer
you may know that it requires some
warm-up linear scheduler
thank you
okay I think it will still take
like two minutes more
so
let's go to the training blog
so this training log will save
uh almost all the information
about your training
so first you need to print it prints out
the command that's good all the
arguments here
there's a prints out the vocabulary size
and we use the Xavier
[Music]
initialization so sometimes I
initialized according to that
and after initializing the model it will
print out
the structure of the model
so our ASR model has a front end
this front end is used to extract the
log male filter Bank features
this part is already covered in the
previous lecture
so I think you are familiar with it
this is a number of furious fft points
this is a window lens the whole size
and some other configurations usually
you do not need to change this
you may need to tune the whole lens
a little bit depending on your
application
and after extracting the features with
your normalize the data using the
collected distance from the previous
stage
so we specify the stats file here
but another option is to use utterance
level mean variance normalization so
that you do not need to collect the
stress this is very helpful if you use a
self supervised learning feature
you can find some examples in other
recipes like Liberty speech but here we
do not use that
and the next part is about encoder so we
have a Transformer encoder
data has several convolution layers at
the beginning
so this will downsample the original
input
so you can adjust the sound sampling
ratio
right specifying this module ESPN
supports some different settings for
this
and this is a
sequential
for 12 encoded layers
from 0 to 11 so it's 12.
and then we have this decoder
which is similar to the previous line
well the last part we have this level
smoothing noise for the attention based
in for the decoder modeling and we have
a CDC loss
and it is two are jointly trained
so it will also show you the learnable
trainable parameters
this model is very small here
and if you want to compare some
different approaches you usually need to
keep this same or similar
and it also brings out the add-on
Optimizer the learning noise scheduler
and also the form the mini batches
so this one is for the training set
because we just specify the best size to
be 64. so this one is pretty simple but
if you use some more advanced adaptive
gratify method
this number can vary across different
batches
and in the training in the initial stage
you can see some
infinite or invalid of grade gradients
this is mainly due to the automatic
mixed precision
but after the first stage everything
looks normal
and you just receive some training laws
Etc
okay I think the training has finished
it
so if you have finished the training we
will
arrive at the checkpoint 3.
in this part you just print the training
log
okay is this card clear to everyone
if your training has not finished you
can just let it go
and after that you print this log
and keep it
okay so next part is decoding
to decode a trained model
we need to specify some additional uh
arguments
if you use language model you need to
set this to be true but here we do not
use it so we disable it and we also
specify the ASI experiment to be this
name distance
and you can change the number of
parallel jobs used for decoding and ESPN
also supports both GPU decoding and CPU
decoding
here I use GPU decoding
and since we only have one GPU so this
part will be one
and you can change the inference config
which is similar to the training review
and here I just run a simple decoding
example with almost the default config
so once the decoding starts you will see
another folder under the experiment
folder
this contains all the information about
your inference job
for example you can check
this inference log
which again prints all the collects all
the necessary information
like this is the decoder architecture
and then it prints out
uh the information for each decoding
sample
for example this sample has this lens
this is the original input lens
and this is the final scores for the two
parts
this is the best hypothesis
it is a yes
okay and I think this part is easy to
understand
that you can change different configures
based on your
user case
this will take like three minutes with a
single GPU
is this
it means real-time Factor so it's based
on the decoding time
before each
has no sense it will generate a sample
folder
and all the information are stored
inside that
this is a lot of files
and this is the score for each
hypothesis generating hypothesis this is
the final text
it has the same architecture as your
training as what we did
during data vibration but this is for
the different inference
Okay so
after the inference we are needed to
compare the generated hypothesis with
the branches
transcript
so we just needed to run the scoring
script
so you can see some results are printed
here
and this part is about the overall
resource but if you want to check
uh the detailed
errors you need to go to
diesel folders any of these folders this
is for good there is token error rate
character error rate
this is a hypothesis this is a branches
and this is a
scoring output
so in this file you can see
and this is organized by different
speakers but we can check the overall
result here this is a number of
sentences number verse the correct rate
the substitution error rate deletion
insertion and the overall error rate
and this is the sentence area rate
so we can see that
I think this is a better rate
is this one
and you can also see
the alignments of different options
so we contain all the alignments
information here this is a reference
this is your hypothesis
this is divisions this is insertion this
is a substitution
and sometimes you
they are the same so
there's no error
okay so here we can see the last
checkpoint
if there's a printout
this results
okay so if you have finished all these
four checkpoints you can now print this
entire notebook and submit it to
grayscope
this contains four points
overall we have five points
so we have two additional exercises you
can finish that after this tutorial
actually in total is six because one
additional bonus
okay since we do not have much time I
will quickly introduce the remaining
content
which is mainly related to your
exercises
so first
how to change the configs this includes
many toolbox the training config and the
inference config
so there are two ways why is the
configure file based we create an uh
training config
and specify it in your command line
you can find the various examples in our
previous
and the other approach is the command
line based
you can specify a specific configure
as an argument positive to the command
so this one has a higher priority ew
overwrite your
configs inside the file
and this is very convenient if you only
want to change a view
configures
with some more advanced usage please
check this documentation
okay
so we can see this is uh the first
exercise
it corresponds to the bonus
but actually the total number is six so
uh
any foot
uh you can submit these exercises after
the class and you can run it again
yeah just before the deadline we will
release the second assignment on
grayscope yeah
so ideally you should finish this before
our Wednesdays tutorial so that it will
be easier
but for the first exercise
we will basically just use the am4 data
set and change the training config
in order to reach a better character
error rate
so here I provide one example with
printable
this is another type of encoder
and I already trained it and get a
results here
I recommend you start with this
configure and tune some other training
configs if you can get a better number
than this one you will get this bonus
this is not difficult
there are some very simple ways to
improve it for example you can choose
you can increase the total number of
webworks and you can
you know so it is pretty simple
but one favorite is that this data set
is very small so the result can be
unstable even using the same config
if you just change the randancy that you
may get some improvement
okay so due to time limit that I will
not show
how to train this model
it's just the same procedure
now if you finish this if you create a
new training config you can run it from
the stage 10 to stage 13 and they show
the results
and I already trained one before the
tutorial so this is my previous result
and you can see that
this is our previous Transformer and
this is a new Transformer result uh
these are on the validation stats
and I only change it as a encoder
architecture all the other training
configures are the same
and this model is actually slightly
larger than the Transformer one is
around the 15 million parameters and the
previous one is around 14.
the final part is how to make a new
recipe this is another exercise
we have prepared some detailed
instructions
in the official report
so this will introduce more details on
what you should do to create a cardi
style data
and there are also prepared a subset of
another small data set for the teachings
tid is here you will use this part to
train a new model and it is also very
small so you can easily finish it
within like 20 minutes of training
I also showed the step-by-step
instructions on how to create a new
recipe
so first you'll need to create a new
folder under this folder under this
paths
and you can just record this script so
that it will prepare some other required
files and Scripts
and after that you need to download the
data
I shared it using Google Drive so you
can download it by just the one line of
code
here
this will be very fast
yes just a few seconds
and this is our newly created recipe you
will see the downloaded data
so
this is a compressed this is the
unzipped one
and we specify
the pass to the script
and the next part is that you'll need to
prepare the data
basically you need to prepare one script
here but this script can call some other
Scripts
so here either calls another python
series
and this local data is already finished
so you just need to create it and copy
this into that
the python script is also almost
refinished but I left a few lines here
so you need to write the remaining files
I think the file will be text and the
answer to speak
so just the two lines of code here
you create it and you copy paste it and
finish it
finally used we just create an entry
points called round of shell which has a
very similar a very simple architecture
structure here
and I have uh modified some of the
configures like the inference config is
passed in the command line
and you can just use this one you don't
need to change it
now for the training configure you just
you can also just use the previous Range
Rover line
the other copies and copy and paste it
and finally repeated the training and
decoded
I saw the one example
so you can see that the address is
already very high and it's a performance
is
actually very good
so similarly Ukraine out the results
okay so this is the second exercise
so all you need to do is to follow these
steps and finish two lines of code in
the data prep python script
at the end of the tutorial I also showed
some more advanced topics
I just share some additional resources
so first is how to find your free
training model
so if you have a new data set which is
very small
we only want to load some load your
model ways from a pre-training model
so this is
supported in usbnet and you can enable
it by just the processing a few
arguments
and the data is a very good tutorial
here showing how to
do this fine building
another very helpful feature is to use
pre-trained a self-supize free training
model
to extract the acoustic features so
previously we mentioned that we just use
the log mineral filter Banks
but if you have a very low resource data
set this plan can give you much better
performance because these models are
pre-trained on huge amounts of unlabeled
data so it can learn very strong
representations
and finally if you want to contribute to
ESPN we have some detailed guidance here
depending on what you want to contribute
you can do take different actions
for example if you create a new recipe
on a new data set and you want to
contribute
then you just follow these parts
you can upload a pre-trained model to
plugins
following some of these steps
and we also have some checklists for you
to check before maker
before making a full request
and if you go to the usbnet refer to
you can see many four requests
yeah you can also check some of the
examples here